<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="configuration.xsl"?>
<!--
Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one or more
contributor license agreements. See the NOTICE file distributed with
this work for additional information regarding copyright ownership.
The ASF licenses this file to You under the Apache License, Version 2.0
(the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at

http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->

<!-- WARNING: THIS IS A GENERATED TEMPLATE PURELY FOR DOCUMENTATION PURPOSES
 AND SHOULD NOT BE USED AS A CONFIGURATION FILE FOR TEZ -->

<configuration>

  <property>
    <name>tez.dag.recovery.enabled</name>
    <defaultValue>true</defaultValue>
    <description>Boolean value. Enable recovery of DAGs. This allows a restarted app master to recover the 
 incomplete DAGs from the previous instance of the app master.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.dag.recovery.io.buffer.size</name>
    <defaultValue>8192</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Size in bytes for the IO buffer size while processing the recovery file.
 Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.dag.recovery.flush.interval.secs</name>
    <defaultValue>30</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Interval, in seconds, between flushing recovery data to the recovery log.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.dag.recovery.max.unflushed.events</name>
    <defaultValue>100</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Number of recovery events to buffer before flushing them to the recovery log.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.heartbeat.timeout.check-ms</name>
    <defaultValue>30000</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Time interval, in milliseconds, between checks for lost tasks.
 Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.timeout-ms</name>
    <defaultValue>300000</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Time interval, in milliseconds, within which a task must heartbeat to the app master
 before its considered lost.
 Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.acls.enabled</name>
    <defaultValue>true</defaultValue>
    <description>Boolean value. Configuration to enable/disable ACL checks.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.allow.disabled.timeline-domains</name>
    <defaultValue>false</defaultValue>
    <description>Boolean value.
 Allow disabling of Timeline Domains even if Timeline is being used.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.client.am.port-range</name>
    <description>String value. Range of ports that the AM can use when binding for client connections. Leave blank
 to use all possible ports. Expert level setting. It&apos;s hadoop standard range configuration.
 For example 50000-50050,50100-50200</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.client.am.thread-count</name>
    <defaultValue>1</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Number of threads to handle client RPC requests. Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.commit-all-outputs-on-dag-success</name>
    <defaultValue>true</defaultValue>
    <description>Boolean value. Determines when the final outputs to data sinks are committed. Commit is an
 output specific operation and typically involves making the output visible for consumption. 
 If the config is true, then the outputs are committed at the end of DAG completion after all 
 constituent vertices have completed. If false, outputs for each vertex are committed after that 
 vertex succeeds. Depending on the desired output visibility and downstream consumer dependencies
 this value must be appropriately chosen. Defaults to the safe choice of true.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.containerlauncher.thread-count-limit</name>
    <defaultValue>500</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Upper limit on the number of threads user to launch containers in the app
 master. Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.container.idle.release-timeout-max.millis</name>
    <defaultValue>10000</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. The maximum amount of time to hold on to a container if no task can be
 assigned to it immediately. Only active when reuse is enabled. The value
 must be +ve and &gt;=
 TezConfiguration#TEZ_AM_CONTAINER_IDLE_RELEASE_TIMEOUT_MIN_MILLIS.
 Containers will have an expire time set to a random value between
 TezConfiguration#TEZ_AM_CONTAINER_IDLE_RELEASE_TIMEOUT_MIN_MILLIS &amp;&amp;
 TezConfiguration#TEZ_AM_CONTAINER_IDLE_RELEASE_TIMEOUT_MAX_MILLIS. This 
 creates a graceful reduction in the amount of idle resources held</description>
    <type>long</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.container.idle.release-timeout-min.millis</name>
    <defaultValue>5000</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. The minimum amount of time to hold on to a container that is idle. Only active when 
 reuse is enabled. Set to -1 to never release idle containers (not recommended).</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.container.reuse.enabled</name>
    <defaultValue>true</defaultValue>
    <description>Boolean value. Configuration to specify whether container should be reused across tasks.
 This improves performance by not incurring recurring launch overheads.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.container.reuse.locality.delay-allocation-millis</name>
    <defaultValue>250</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. The amount of time to wait before assigning a container to the next level
 of locality. NODE -&gt; RACK -&gt; NON_LOCAL. Delay scheduling parameter. Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>long</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.container.reuse.non-local-fallback.enabled</name>
    <defaultValue>false</defaultValue>
    <description>Boolean value. Whether to reuse containers for non-local tasks. Active only if reuse is
 enabled. Turning this on can severely affect locality and can be bad for jobs with high data 
 volume being read from the primary data sources.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.container.reuse.rack-fallback.enabled</name>
    <defaultValue>true</defaultValue>
    <description>Boolean value. Whether to reuse containers for rack local tasks. Active only if reuse is
 enabled.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.credentials-merge</name>
    <description>Boolean value. If true then Tez will add the ApplicationMaster credentials
 to all task credentials.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.dag.scheduler.class</name>
    <defaultValue>org.apache.tez.dag.app.dag.impl.DAGSchedulerNaturalOrder</defaultValue>
    <description>String value. The class to be used for DAG Scheduling. Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.disable.client-version-check</name>
    <defaultValue>false</defaultValue>
    <description>Boolean value.
 Disable version check between client and AM/DAG. Default false.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.inline.task.execution.enabled</name>
    <defaultValue>false</defaultValue>
    <description>Tez AM Inline Mode flag. Not valid till Tez-684 get checked-in</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.inline.task.execution.max-tasks</name>
    <defaultValue>1</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value.
 The maximium number of tasks running in parallel within the app master process.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.launch.cluster-default.cmd-opts</name>
    <defaultValue>-server -Djava.net.preferIPv4Stack=true -Dhadoop.metrics.log.level=WARN</defaultValue>
    <description>String value. Command line options which will be prepended to {@link #TEZ_AM_LAUNCH_CMD_OPTS}
 during the launch of the AppMaster process. This property will typically be configured to
 include default options meant to be used by all jobs in a cluster. If required, the values can
 be overridden per job.</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.launch.cluster-default.env</name>
    <description>String value. Env settings will be merged with {@link #TEZ_AM_LAUNCH_ENV}
 during the launch of the AppMaster process. This property will typically be configured to
 include default system env meant to be used by all jobs in a cluster. If required, the values can
 be appended to per job.</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.launch.cmd-opts</name>
    <defaultValue>-XX:+PrintGCDetails -verbose:gc -XX:+PrintGCTimeStamps -XX:+UseNUMA -XX:+UseParallelGC</defaultValue>
    <description>String value. Command line options provided during the launch of the Tez
 AppMaster process. Its recommended to not set any Xmx or Xms in these launch opts so that
 Tez can determine them automatically.</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.launch.env</name>
    <description>String value. Env settings for the Tez AppMaster process.
 Should be specified as a comma-separated of key-value pairs where each pair
 is defined as KEY=VAL
 e.g. &quot;LD_LIBRARY_PATH=.,USERNAME=foo&quot;
 These take least precedence compared to other methods of setting env.
 These get added to the app master environment prior to launching it.
 This setting will prepend existing settings in the cluster default</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.legacy.speculative.slowtask.threshold</name>
    <description>Float value. Specifies how many standard deviations away from the mean task execution time 
 should be considered as an outlier/slow task.</description>
    <type>float</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.log.level</name>
    <defaultValue>INFO</defaultValue>
    <description>Root Logging level passed to the Tez app master.

 Simple configuration: Set the log level for all loggers.
   e.g. INFO
   This sets the log level to INFO for all loggers.

 Advanced configuration: Set the log level for all classes, along with a different level for some.
   e.g. DEBUG;org.apache.hadoop.ipc=INFO;org.apache.hadoop.security=INFO
   This sets the log level for all loggers to DEBUG, expect for the
   org.apache.hadoop.ipc and org.apache.hadoop.security, which are set to INFO

 Note: The global log level must always be the first parameter.
   DEBUG;org.apache.hadoop.ipc=INFO;org.apache.hadoop.security=INFO is valid
   org.apache.hadoop.ipc=INFO;org.apache.hadoop.security=INFO is not valid</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.max.allowed.time-sec.for-read-error</name>
    <defaultValue>300</defaultValue>
    <description>int value. Represents the maximum time in seconds for which a consumer attempt can report 
 a read error against its producer attempt, after which the producer attempt will be re-run 
 to re-generate the output. There are other heuristics which determine the retry and mainly 
 try to guard against a flurry of re-runs due to intermittent read errors 
 (due to network issues). This configuration puts a time limit on those heuristics to ensure
 jobs dont hang indefinitely due to lack of closure in those heuristics 

 Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.max.app.attempts</name>
    <defaultValue>2</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Specifies the number of times the app master can be launched in order to recover 
 from app master failure. Typically app master failures are non-recoverable. This parameter 
 is for cases where the app master is not at fault but is lost due to system errors.
 Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.maxtaskfailures.per.node</name>
    <defaultValue>10</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Specifies the number of task failures on a node before the node is considered faulty.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.modify-acls</name>
    <description>String value.
 AM modify ACLs. This allows the specified users/groups to run modify operations on the AM
 such as submitting DAGs, pre-warming the session, killing DAGs or shutting down the session.
 Comma separated list of users, followed by whitespace, followed by a comma separated list of 
 groups</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.node-blacklisting.enabled</name>
    <defaultValue>true</defaultValue>
    <description>Boolean value. Enabled blacklisting of nodes of nodes that are considered faulty. These nodes 
 will not be used to execute tasks.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.node-blacklisting.ignore-threshold-node-percent</name>
    <defaultValue>33</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Specifies the percentage of nodes in the cluster that may be considered faulty.
 This limits the number of nodes that are blacklisted in an effort to minimize the effects of 
 temporary surges in failures (e.g. due to network outages).</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.node-unhealthy-reschedule-tasks</name>
    <defaultValue>false</defaultValue>
    <description>Boolean value. Enable task rescheduling for node updates.
 When enabled the task scheduler will reschedule task attempts that
 are associated with an unhealthy node to avoid potential data transfer
 errors from downstream tasks.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.preemption.heartbeats-between-preemptions</name>
    <defaultValue>3</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. The number of RM heartbeats to wait after preempting running tasks before preempting
 more running tasks. After preempting a task, we need to wait at least 1 heartbeat so that the 
 RM can act on the released resources and assign new ones to us. Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.preemption.max.wait-time-ms</name>
    <defaultValue>60000</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Time (in millisecs) that an unsatisfied request will wait before preempting other
 resources. In rare cases, the cluster says there are enough free resources but does not end 
 up getting enough on a node to actually assign it to the job. This configuration tries to put 
 a deadline on such wait to prevent indefinite job hangs.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.preemption.percentage</name>
    <defaultValue>10</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Specifies the percentage of tasks eligible to be preempted that
 will actually be preempted in a given round of Tez internal preemption.
 This slows down preemption and gives more time for free resources to be
 allocated by the cluster (if any) and gives more time for preemptable tasks
 to finish. Valid values are 0-100. Higher values will preempt quickly at
 the cost of losing work. Setting to 0 turns off preemption. Expert level
 setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.resource.cpu.vcores</name>
    <defaultValue>1</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. The number of virtual cores to be used by the app master</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.resource.memory.mb</name>
    <defaultValue>1024</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. The amount of memory in MB to be used by the AppMaster</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.am-rm.heartbeat.interval-ms.max</name>
    <defaultValue>1000</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. The maximum heartbeat interval between the AM and RM in milliseconds
 Increasing this reduces the communication between the AM and the RM and can
 help in scaling up. Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.session.min.held-containers</name>
    <defaultValue>0</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. The minimum number of containers that will be held in session mode. Not active in 
 non-session mode. Enables an idle session (not running any DAG) to hold on to a minimum number
 of containers to provide fast response times for the next DAG.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.mode.session</name>
    <defaultValue>false</defaultValue>
    <description>Boolean value. Execution mode for the Tez application. True implies session mode. If the client
 code is written according to best practices then the same code can execute in either mode based
 on this configuration. Session mode is more aggressive in reserving execution resources and is
 typically used for interactive applications where multiple DAGs are submitted in quick succession
 by the same user. For long running applications, one-off executions, batch jobs etc non-session 
 mode is recommended. If session mode is enabled then container reuse is recommended.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.speculation.enabled</name>
    <defaultValue>false</defaultValue>
    <type>boolean</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.staging-dir</name>
    <description>String value. Specifies a directory where Tez can create temporary job artifacts.</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.staging.scratch-data.auto-delete</name>
    <defaultValue>true</defaultValue>
    <description>Boolean value. If true then Tez will try to automatically delete temporary job 
 artifacts that it creates within the specified staging dir. Does not affect any user data.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.task.listener.thread-count</name>
    <defaultValue>30</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. The number of threads used to listen to task heartbeat requests.
 Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.task.max.failed.attempts</name>
    <defaultValue>4</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. The maximum number of attempts that can fail for a particular task before the task is failed. 
 This does not count killed attempts. Task failure results in DAG failure.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.tez-ui.history-url.template</name>
    <defaultValue>__HISTORY_URL_BASE__/#/tez-app/__APPLICATION_ID__</defaultValue>
    <description>String value
 Tez UI URL template for the application.
 Expert level setting.

 The AM will redirect the user to the Tez UI via this url. Template supports the following
 parameters to be replaced with the actual runtime information:

   __APPLICATION_ID__ : Replaces this with application ID
   __HISTORY_URL_BASE__: replaces this with TEZ_HISTORY_URL_BASE

   For example, &quot;http://uihost:9001/#/tez-app/__APPLICATION_ID__/ will be replaced to
   http://uihost:9001/#/tez-app/application_1421880306565_0001/</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.vertex.max-task-concurrency</name>
    <defaultValue>-1</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. The maximum number of attempts that can run concurrently for a given vertex.
 Setting &lt;=0 implies no limit</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.view-acls</name>
    <description>String value. 
 AM view ACLs. This allows the specified users/groups to view the status of the AM and all DAGs
 that run within this AM.
 Comma separated list of users, followed by whitespace, followed by a comma separated list of 
 groups</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.tez-ui.webservice.enable</name>
    <defaultValue>true</defaultValue>
    <description>String value
 Allow disabling of the Tez AM webservice. If set to false the Tez-UI wont show progress
 updates for running application.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.application.tags</name>
    <description>String value. Tags for the job that will be passed to YARN at submission
 time. Queries to YARN for applications can filter on these tags.</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.aux.uris</name>
    <description>Auxiliary resources to be localized for the Tez AM and all its containers.

 Value is comma-separated list of fully-resolved directories or file paths. All resources
 are made available into the working directory of the AM and/or containers i.e. $CWD.

 If directories are specified, they are not traversed recursively. Only files directly under the
 specified directory are localized.

 All duplicate resources are ignored.</description>
    <type>string</type>
    <value>${fs.defaultFS}/apps/tez</value>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.cancel.delegation.tokens.on.completion</name>
    <defaultValue>true</defaultValue>
    <type>boolean</type>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.client.asynchronous-stop</name>
    <defaultValue>true</defaultValue>
    <description>Boolean value. Backwards compatibility setting. Changes TezClient stop to be a
 synchronous call waiting until AM is in a final state before returning to the user.
 Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.client.diagnostics.wait.timeout-ms</name>
    <defaultValue>3000</defaultValue>
    <description>Long value
 Time to wait (in milliseconds) for yarn app&apos;s diagnotics is available
 Workaround for YARN-2560</description>
    <type>long</type>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.client.timeout-ms</name>
    <defaultValue>30000</defaultValue>
    <description>Long value. Time interval, in milliseconds, for client to wait during client-requested
 AM shutdown before issuing a hard kill to the RM for this application.
 Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>long</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.java.opts.checker.class</name>
    <description>String value.
 Ability to provide a different implementation to check/verify java opts defined
 for vertices/tasks.
 Class has to be an instance of JavaOptsChecker</description>
    <type>string</type>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.java.opts.checker.enabled</name>
    <defaultValue>true</defaultValue>
    <description>Boolean value. Default true.
 Ability to disable the Java Opts Checker</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.container.max.java.heap.fraction</name>
    <defaultValue>0.8</defaultValue>
    <description>Double value. Tez automatically determines the Xmx for the JVMs used to run
 Tez tasks and app masters. This feature is enabled if the user has not
 specified Xmx or Xms values in the launch command opts. Doing automatic Xmx
 calculation is preferred because Tez can determine the best value based on
 actual allocation of memory to tasks the cluster. The value if used as a
 fraction that is applied to the memory allocated Factor to size Xmx based
 on container memory size. Value should be greater than 0 and less than 1.</description>
    <type>float</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.counters.counter-name.max-length</name>
    <defaultValue>64</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Configuration to limit the length of counter names. This can be used to
 limit the amount of memory being used in the app master to store the
 counters. Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.counters.group-name.max-length</name>
    <defaultValue>256</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Configuration to limit the counter group names per app master. This can be used to
 limit the amount of memory being used in the app master to store the
 counters. Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.counters.max</name>
    <defaultValue>1200</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Configuration to limit the counters per dag (AppMaster and Task). This can be used
 to
 limit the amount of memory being used in the app master to store the
 counters. Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.counters.max.groups</name>
    <defaultValue>500</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Configuration to limit the number of counter groups for a DAG. This can be used to
 limit the amount of memory being used in the app master to store the
 counters. Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.credentials.path</name>
    <description>String value that is a file path.
 Path to a credentials file (with serialized credentials) located on the local file system.</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.dag.status.pollinterval-ms</name>
    <defaultValue>500</defaultValue>
    <description>Long value
 Status Poll interval in Milliseconds used when getting DAG status with timeout.</description>
    <type>long</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.generate.debug.artifacts</name>
    <defaultValue>false</defaultValue>
    <type>boolean</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.history.logging.log.level</name>
    <description>Enum value. Config to limit the type of events published to the history logging service.
 The valid log levels are defined in the enum {@link HistoryLogLevel}. The default value is
 defined in {@link HistoryLogLevel#DEFAULT}.</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.history.logging.service.class</name>
    <defaultValue>org.apache.tez.dag.history.logging.impl.SimpleHistoryLoggingService</defaultValue>
    <description>String value that is a class name.
 Specify the class to use for logging history data.
 To disable, set this to &quot;org.apache.tez.dag.history.logging.impl.DevNullHistoryLoggingService&quot;</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.history.logging.taskattempt-filters</name>
    <description>List of comma separated enum values. Specifies the list of task attempt termination causes,
 which have to be suppressed from being logged to ATS. The valid filters are defined in the
 enum TaskAttemptTerminationCause. The filters are applied only if tez.history.logging.log.level
 is set to TASK_ATTEMPT.</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.history.logging.timeline-cache-plugin.old-num-dags-per-group</name>
    <description>Comma separated list of Integers. These are the values that were set for the config value
 for {@value #TEZ_HISTORY_LOGGING_TIMELINE_NUM_DAGS_PER_GROUP}. The older values are required so
 that the groupIds generated previously will continue to be generated by the plugin. If an older
 value is not present then the UI may not show information for DAGs which were created
 with a different grouping value.

 Note: Do not add too many values here as it will affect the performance of Yarn Timeline
 Server/Tez UI due to the need to scan for more log files.</description>
    <type>string</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.history.logging.timeline.num-dags-per-group</name>
    <defaultValue>1</defaultValue>
    <description>Integer value. Number of DAGs to be grouped together. This is used by the history logging
 service to generate groupIds such that numDagsPerGroup will have same groupId in a given
 session. If the value is set to 1 then we disable grouping. This config is used to control the
 number of DAGs written into one log file, and hence controls number of files created in
 the Filesystem used by YARN Timeline.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.tez-ui.history-url.base</name>
    <description>String value
 Tez-UI Url base. This gets replaced in the TEZ_AM_TEZ_UI_HISTORY_URL_TEMPLATE
 ex http://ui-host:9001 or if its hosted with a prefix http://ui-host:9001/~user
 if the ui is hosted on the default port (80 for http and 443 for https), the port should not
 be specified.</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.ignore.lib.uris</name>
    <description>Boolean value. Allows to ignore &apos;tez.lib.uris&apos;. Useful during development as well as 
 raw Tez application where classpath is propagated with application
 via {@link LocalResource}s. This is mainly useful for developer/debugger scenarios.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.ipc.payload.reserved.bytes</name>
    <defaultValue>5242880</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. SubmitDAGPlanRequest cannot be larger than Max IPC message size minus this number; otherwise, it will
 be serialized to HDFS and we transfer the path to server. Server will deserialize the request from HDFS.</description>
    <type>int</type>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.tez.jvm.system-properties-to-log</name>
    <description>String value. Determines what JVM properties will be logged for debugging purposes
 in the AM and Task runtime logs.</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.lib.uris</name>
    <description>String value to a file path.
 The location of the Tez libraries which will be localized for DAGs.
 This follows the following semantics
 &lt;ol&gt;
 &lt;li&gt; To use .tar.gz or .tgz files (generated by the tez or hadoop builds), the full path to this
 file (including filename) should be specified. The internal structure of the uncompressed tgz
 will be defined by &apos;tez.lib.uris.classpath&apos;&lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt; If a single file is specified without the above mentioned extensions - it will be treated as
 a regular file. This means it will not be uncompressed during runtime. &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt; If multiple entries exist
 &lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt; Regular Files: will be treated as regular files (not uncompressed during runtime) &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt; Archive Files: will be treated as archives and will be uncompressed during runtime &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt; Directories: all files under the directory (non-recursive) will be made available (but not
 uncompressed during runtime). &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    <type>string</type>
    <value>${fs.defaultFS}/apps/apache-tez-0.8.5-bin.tar.gz</value>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.lib.uris.classpath</name>
    <description>Specify additional user classpath information to be used for Tez AM and all containers.
 This will be appended to the classpath after PWD
 
 &apos;tez.lib.uris.classpath&apos; defines the relative classpath into the archives
 that are set in &apos;tez.lib.uris&apos;</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.local.mode</name>
    <defaultValue>false</defaultValue>
    <description>Boolean value. Enable local mode execution in Tez. Enables tasks to run in the same process as
  the app master. Primarily used for debugging.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.queue.name</name>
    <description>String value. The queue name for all jobs being submitted from a given client.</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.session.am.dag.submit.timeout.secs</name>
    <defaultValue>300</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Time (in seconds) for which the Tez AM should wait for a DAG to be submitted before
 shutting down. Only relevant in session mode. Any negative value will disable this check and
 allow the AM to hang around forever in idle mode.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.session.client.timeout.secs</name>
    <defaultValue>120</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Time (in seconds) to wait for AM to come up when trying to submit a DAG
 from the client. Only relevant in session mode. If the cluster is busy and cannot launch the 
 AM then this timeout may be hit. In those case, using non-session mode is recommended if 
 applicable. Otherwise increase the timeout (set to -1 for infinity. Not recommended)</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.simple.history.logging.dir</name>
    <description>String value. The directory into which history data will be written. This defaults to the 
 container logging directory. This is relevant only when SimpleHistoryLoggingService is being
 used for {@link TezConfiguration#TEZ_HISTORY_LOGGING_SERVICE_CLASS}</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.simple.history.max.errors</name>
    <defaultValue>10</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Maximum errors allowed while logging history data. After crossing this limit history
 logging gets disabled. The job continues to run after this.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.am.heartbeat.counter.interval-ms.max</name>
    <defaultValue>4000</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Interval, in milliseconds, after which counters are sent to AM in heartbeat from 
 tasks. This reduces the amount of network traffice between AM and tasks to send high-volume 
 counters. Improves AM scalability. Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.am.heartbeat.interval-ms.max</name>
    <defaultValue>100</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. The maximum heartbeat interval, in milliseconds, between the app master and tasks. 
 Increasing this can help improve app master scalability for a large number of concurrent tasks.
 Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.generate.counters.per.io</name>
    <defaultValue>false</defaultValue>
    <description>Whether to generate counters per IO or not. Enabling this will rename
 CounterGroups / CounterNames to making them unique per Vertex +
 Src|Destination</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.get-task.sleep.interval-ms.max</name>
    <defaultValue>200</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. The maximum amount of time, in milliseconds, to wait before a task asks an
 AM for another task. Increasing this can help improve app master scalability for a large 
 number of concurrent tasks. Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.initialize-processor-first</name>
    <defaultValue>false</defaultValue>
    <description>Boolean value. Backwards compatibility setting for initializing IO processor before
 inputs and outputs.
 Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.initialize-processor-io-serially</name>
    <defaultValue>false</defaultValue>
    <description>Boolean value. Backwards compatibility setting for initializing inputs and outputs
 serially instead of the parallel default.
 Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.launch.cluster-default.cmd-opts</name>
    <defaultValue>-server -Djava.net.preferIPv4Stack=true -Dhadoop.metrics.log.level=WARN</defaultValue>
    <description>String value. Command line options which will be prepended to {@link
 #TEZ_TASK_LAUNCH_CMD_OPTS} during the launch of Tez tasks.  This property will typically be configured to
 include default options meant to be used by all jobs in a cluster. If required, the values can
 be overridden per job.</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.launch.cluster-default.env</name>
    <description>String value. Env settings will be merged with {@link #TEZ_TASK_LAUNCH_ENV}
 during the launch of the task process. This property will typically be configured to
 include default system env meant to be used by all jobs in a cluster. If required, the values can
 be appended to per job.</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.launch.cmd-opts</name>
    <defaultValue>-XX:+PrintGCDetails -verbose:gc -XX:+PrintGCTimeStamps -XX:+UseNUMA -XX:+UseParallelGC</defaultValue>
    <description>String value. Command line options provided during the launch of Tez Task
 processes. Its recommended to not set any Xmx or Xms in these launch opts
 so that Tez can determine them automatically.</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.launch.env</name>
    <description>String value. Env settings for the Tez Task processes.
 Should be specified as a comma-separated of key-value pairs where each pair
 is defined as KEY=VAL
 e.g. &quot;LD_LIBRARY_PATH=.,USERNAME=foo&quot;
 These take least precedence compared to other methods of setting env
 These get added to the task environment prior to launching it.
 This setting will prepend existing settings in the cluster default</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.log.level</name>
    <defaultValue>INFO</defaultValue>
    <description>Root Logging level passed to the Tez tasks.

 Simple configuration: Set the log level for all loggers.
   e.g. INFO
   This sets the log level to INFO for all loggers.

 Advanced configuration: Set the log level for all classes, along with a different level for some.
   e.g. DEBUG;org.apache.hadoop.ipc=INFO;org.apache.hadoop.security=INFO
   This sets the log level for all loggers to DEBUG, expect for the
   org.apache.hadoop.ipc and org.apache.hadoop.security, which are set to INFO

 Note: The global log level must always be the first parameter.
   DEBUG;org.apache.hadoop.ipc=INFO;org.apache.hadoop.security=INFO is valid
   org.apache.hadoop.ipc=INFO;org.apache.hadoop.security=INFO is not valid</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.max-events-per-heartbeat</name>
    <defaultValue>500</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Maximum number of of events to fetch from the AM by the tasks in a single heartbeat.
 Expert level setting. Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.max-event-backlog</name>
    <defaultValue>10000</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Maximum number of pending task events before a task will stop
 asking for more events in the task heartbeat.
 Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.progress.stuck.interval-ms</name>
    <defaultValue>-1</defaultValue>
    <description>Long value. Interval, in milliseconds, within which any of the tasks Input/Processor/Output 
 components need to make successive progress notifications. If the progress is not notified 
 for this interval then the task will be considered hung and terminated.
 The value for this config should be larger than {@link TezConfiguration#TASK_HEARTBEAT_TIMEOUT_MS} 
 and larger than 2 times the value of {@link TezConfiguration#TEZ_TASK_AM_HEARTBEAT_INTERVAL_MS}.
 A config value &lt;=0 disables this.</description>
    <type>string</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.resource.calculator.process-tree.class</name>
    <type>string</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.resource.cpu.vcores</name>
    <defaultValue>1</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. The number of virtual cores to be used by tasks.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.resource.memory.mb</name>
    <defaultValue>1024</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. The amount of memory in MB to be used by tasks. This applies to all tasks across
 all vertices. Setting it to the same value for all tasks is helpful for container reuse and 
 thus good for performance typically.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.scale.memory.additional-reservation.fraction.max</name>
    <type>float</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.scale.memory.additional-reservation.fraction.per-io</name>
    <description>Fraction of available memory to reserve per input/output. This amount is
 removed from the total available pool before allocation and is for factoring in overheads.</description>
    <type>float</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.scale.memory.allocator.class</name>
    <defaultValue>org.apache.tez.runtime.library.resources.WeightedScalingMemoryDistributor</defaultValue>
    <description>The allocator to use for initial memory allocation</description>
    <type>string</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.scale.memory.enabled</name>
    <defaultValue>true</defaultValue>
    <description>Whether to scale down memory requested by each component if the total
 exceeds the available JVM memory</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.scale.memory.reserve-fraction</name>
    <defaultValue>0.3</defaultValue>
    <description>The fraction of the JVM memory which will not be considered for allocation.
 No defaults, since there are pre-existing defaults based on different scenarios.</description>
    <type>double</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task.scale.memory.ratios</name>
    <type>string</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task-specific.launch.cmd-opts</name>
    <description>Additional launch command options to be added for specific tasks.
 __VERTEX_NAME__ and __TASK_INDEX__ can be specified, which would be replaced at
 runtime by vertex name and task index.
 e.g tez.task-specific.launch.cmd-opts=
 &quot;-agentpath:libpagent.so,dir=/tmp/__VERTEX_NAME__/__TASK_INDEX__&quot;</description>
    <type>string</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task-specific.launch.cmd-opts.list</name>
    <description>Set of tasks for which specific launch command options need to be added.
 Format: &quot;vertexName[csv of task ids];vertexName[csv of task ids]..&quot;
 Valid e.g:
 v[0,1,2]  - Additional launch-cmd options for tasks 0,1,2 of vertex v
 v[1,2,3];v2[5,6,7] - Additional launch-cmd options specified for tasks of vertices v and v2.
 v[1:5,20,30];v2[2:5,60,7] - Additional launch-cmd options for 1,2,3,4,5,20,30 of vertex v; 2,
 3,4,5,60,7 of vertex v2
 Partial ranges like :5, 1: are not supported.
 v[] - Additional launch-cmd options for all tasks in vertex v</description>
    <type>string</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.task-specific.log.level</name>
    <description>Task specific log level.

 Simple configuration: Set the log level for all loggers.
   e.g. INFO
   This sets the log level to INFO for all loggers.

 Advanced configuration: Set the log level for all classes, along with a different level for some.
   e.g. DEBUG;org.apache.hadoop.ipc=INFO;org.apache.hadoop.security=INFO
   This sets the log level for all loggers to DEBUG, expect for the
   org.apache.hadoop.ipc and org.apache.hadoop.security, which are set to INFO

 Note: The global log level must always be the first parameter.
   DEBUG;org.apache.hadoop.ipc=INFO;org.apache.hadoop.security=INFO is valid
   org.apache.hadoop.ipc=INFO;org.apache.hadoop.security=INFO is not valid</description>
    <type>string</type>
    <unstable>true</unstable>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.test.minicluster.app.wait.on.shutdown.secs</name>
    <defaultValue>30</defaultValue>
    <description>Long value.
 Time to wait (in seconds) for apps to complete on MiniTezCluster shutdown.</description>
    <type>long</type>
    <private>true</private>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.use.cluster.hadoop-libs</name>
    <defaultValue>false</defaultValue>
    <description>Boolean value.
 Specify whether hadoop libraries required to run Tez should be the ones deployed on the cluster.
 This is disabled by default - with the expectation being that tez.lib.uris has a complete
 tez-deployment which contains the hadoop libraries.</description>
    <type>boolean</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.yarn.ats.acl.domains.auto-create</name>
    <defaultValue>true</defaultValue>
    <type>boolean</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.yarn.ats.event.flush.timeout.millis</name>
    <defaultValue>-1</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Time, in milliseconds, to wait while flushing YARN ATS data during shutdown.
 Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>long</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.yarn.ats.max.events.per.batch</name>
    <defaultValue>5</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Max no. of events to send in a single batch to ATS.
 Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.yarn.ats.max.polling.time.per.event.millis</name>
    <defaultValue>10</defaultValue>
    <description>Int value. Time, in milliseconds, to wait for an event before sending a batch to ATS.
 Expert level setting.</description>
    <type>integer</type>
  </property>

</configuration>
